A Guide to the June Barrows Mussey Papers 1813-1989
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
June Barrows Mussey Papers 1813-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10890
There are 960 items in this collection.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Mrs. Barrows Mussey through the Rare Book Division of the Special Collections Department on December 18, 1989.
Alternative Form
Originals of this collection are at Harvard University Archives, New Haven Colony Historical Society, Yale University, and the National Archives.
Scope and Content Information
This research collection about Samuel Griswold Goodrich (pen name Peter Parley) (1793-1851), as compiled by June Barrows Mussey (1910-1985) contains ca. 960 items, 1813-1989. Included are two original letters of Goodrich along with electrostatic copies from various repositories of his correspondence, consular dispatches, articles, and books. There are also publishers and booksellers contracts and receipts of William James Hamersley which includes a contract, February 7, 1852, by which Chauncey A[llen] Goodrich (1790-1852) conveys his right, title, and interest to the book C. C. Hachenberg, Elements of Greek Grammar. Other items include Mussey's correspondence with associates and repositories concerning Goodrich, and prints of Goodrich. Material concerning Barrows include biographical sketches and photographs, and a collection of bookplates of the Merrythought Press.
Contents List
- ORIGINAL CORRESPONDENCE AND PAPERS
  - Papers of Samuel Griswold Goodrich 1828-1860 (Box 1)
  - Publishers and Booksellers Contracts and Receipts of William James Hamersley 1836-1863 (Box 1)
- RESEARCH MATERIAL RE: SAMUEL GRISWOLD GOODRICH
  - Copies of Consular Dispatches of S.G. Goodrich in Paris 1851-1857, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Copies of Letters of Samuel Griswold Goodrich (from various repositories) 1819-1852, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Copies of Letters of Samuel Griswold Goodrich (from a private owner) (1813-1856) 1895 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence of June Barrows Mussey with associates and institutions re: Samuel Griswold Goodrich 1969-1983 (Box 2)
  - Material re: Samuel Griswold Goodrich 1967-1976, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Material re: Samuel Griswold Goodrich's friends & contemporaries 1972-1976, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Material re: Samuel Griswold Goodrich's relatives 1969, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Notes and Printed Material re: Samuel Griswold Goodrich 1966-1978, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Samuel Griswold Goodrich n.d. (Box 2)
  - "The Commecial History of Penny Magazine," The Penny Magazine 1833, electrostatic copy (Box 2)
  - Peter Parley's Ausgewahlte Erzahlungen [Selected Tales]ca. 1855, 1983, electrostatic copy (Box 2)
  - Peter Parley's "Ireland and the Irish," The Token and Atlantic Souvenir1841, 1982, electrostatic copy (Box 2)
- MATERIAL RE: JUNE BARROWS MUSSEY
  - June Barrows Mussey: Biographies and Photographs 1925, 1970-1989 (Box 2)
  - Merrythought Book Labels n.d. (Box 2)
  - (Box 2)